A Guide to the Princess Anne County (Va.) Judgments, 1750-1913
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Princess Anne County (Va.) Judgments, 1750-1913
Library of Virginia
1119972-1120085, 1146214-1146237, 1183640-1183672
70.55 cu. ft. (154 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came in a transfer of court papers from Princess Anne County.
Historical Information
Princess Anne County was named for Anne, daughter of King James II, who became queen of England in 1702. The county was formed from Lower Norfolk County in 1691 and became extinct on 1 January 1963, after its consolidation with the city of Virginia Beach. The county seat was Princess Anne.
Scope and Content
Princess Anne County (Va.) Judgments, 1750-1913, contain civil cases heard in County Court, Superior Court of Law, Circuit Superior Court, and Circuit Court in which justice was administered on the strictly formulated rules of common law. The majority of cases in this record series relate to matters of debt.
Arrangement
Chronological (Cases filed within each box by month and year they were resolved.)
Access Terms
Virginia Beach (Va.) -- Circuit Court.; Civil procedure -- Virginia -- Princess Anne County.; Debt -- Virginia -- Princess Anne County.; Public Records -- Virginia -- Princess Anne County.; Princess Anne County (Va.) -- History.; Virginia Beach (Va.) -- History.; Decisions -- Virginia -- Princess Anne County.; Judicial records -- Virginia -- Princess Anne County.; Local government records -- Virginia -- Princess Anne County.; Princess Anne County (Va.) -- Circuit Superior Court of Law and Chancery.; Princess Anne County (Va.) -- County Court.; Princess Anne County (Va.) -- Superior Court of Law.
Contents List
- Judgments 1750-1790 (Barcode 1119973)
- Judgments 1791 (Barcode 1119972)
- Judgments 1792 (Barcode 1119976)
- Judgments 1793 (Barcode 1119983)
- Judgments 1794 (Barcode 1119980)
- Judgments 1795 (Barcode 1119979)
- Judgments 1796 (Barcode 1119981)
- Judgments 1797 (Barcode 1119978)
- Judgments 1798-1799 (Barcode 1119982)
- Judgments 1800-1801 (Barcode 1119987)
- Judgments 1802-1803 (Barcode 1119984)
- Judgments 1804 (Barcode 1119986)
- Judgments 1805 (Barcode 1119985)
- Judgments 1806 (Barcode 1119989)
- Judgments 1807-1808 (Barcode 1119988)
- Judgments 1808-1859 (Barcode 1120085)
- Judgments 1809-1810 (Barcode 1119991)
- Judgments 1809-1816 (Barcode 1120038)
- Judgments 1811-1812 (Barcode 1119995)
- Judgments 1813-1815 (Barcode 1119992)
- Judgments 1816-1817 (Barcode 1119990)
- Judgments 1817-1818 (Barcode 1120039)
- Judgments 1818 (Barcode 1119994)
- Judgments 1819 (Barcode 1119993)
- Judgments 1819-1821 (Barcode 1120040)
- Judgments 1820 (Barcode 1120001)
- Judgments 1821-1822 (Barcode 1120000)
- Judgments 1822-1823 (Barcode 1120041)
- Judgments 1823 (Barcode 1119999)
- Judgments 1824 (Barcode 1119997)
- Judgments 1824 (Barcode 1119998)
- Judgments 1824-1827 (Barcode 1120044)
- Judgments 1825 (Barcode 1119996)
- Judgments 1826 (Barcode 1120007)
- Judgments 1827 (Barcode 1120006)
- Judgments 1828 (Barcode 1120005)
- Judgments 1828-1831 (Barcode 1120045)
- Judgments 1829-1830 (Barcode 1120004)
- Judgments 1831 (Barcode 1120002)
- Judgments 1831-1834 (Barcode 1120046)
- Judgments 1832 (Barcode 1120003)
- Judgments 1833 (Barcode 1120011)
- Judgments 1834 (Barcode 1120010)
- Judgments 1835-1836 (Barcode 1120008)
- Judgments 1835-1837 (Barcode 1120047)
- Judgments 1837-1838 (Barcode 1120013)
- Judgments 1838, 1840-1841 (Barcode 1120048)
- Judgments 1839-1840 (Barcode 1120012)
- Judgments 1841 (Barcode 1120009)
- Judgments 1842 (Barcode 1120014)
- Judgments 1842-1843 (Barcode 1120049)
- Judgments 1843 (Barcode 1120015)
- Judgments 1844-1845 (Barcode 1120016)
- Judgments 1844-1845 (Barcode 1120050)
- Judgments 1846-1848 (Barcode 1120017)
- Judgments 1846-1848 (Barcode 1120052)
- Judgments 1849-1853 (Barcode 1120018)
- Judgments 1849-1850 (Barcode 1120055)
- Judgments 1851-1852 (Barcode 1120054)
- Judgments 1853-1854 (Barcode 1120051)
- Judgments 1854-1856 (Barcode 1120019)
- Judgments 1855-1857 (Barcode 1120053)
- Judgments 1857-1859 (Barcode 1120020)
- Judgments 1858-1860; 1862 (Barcode 1120056)
- Judgments 1860-1863, 1865 (Barcode 1120021)
- Judgments 1866 (Barcode 1120022)
- Judgments 1866 (Barcode 1120023)
- Judgments 1866-1868 (Barcode 1120058)
- Judgments 1867 (Barcode 1120025)
- Judgments 1868 (Barcode 1120024)
- Judgments 1869 (Barcode 1120026)
- Judgments 1869-1874 (Barcode 1120060)
- Judgments 1870 (Barcode 1120027)
- Judgments 1871-1872 (Barcode 1120028)
- Judgments 1873-1876 (Barcode 1120029)
- Judgments 1875-1876 (Barcode 1120057)
- Judgments 1877-1880 (Barcode 1120030)
- Judgments 1877-1879 (Barcode 1120059)
- Judgments 1880-1885 (Barcode 1120061)
- Judgments 1881-1884 (Barcode 1120031)
- Judgments 1885-1888 (Barcode 1120032)
- Judgments 1886-1891 (Barcode 1120067)
- Judgments 1889-1891 (Barcode 1120035)
- Judgments 1892-1895 (Barcode 1120036)
- Judgments 1892-1896 (Barcode 1120066)
- Judgments 1896-1898 (Barcode 1120034)
- Judgments 1897-1901 (Barcode 1120062)
- Judgments 1899-1901 (Barcode 1120033)
- Judgments: Commonwealth v. Fleming 1900-1901 (Barcode 1120063)
- Judgments 1902-1904 (Barcode 1120037)
- Judgments 1902-1904 (Barcode 1120064)
- Judgments 1905-1906 (Barcode 1120065)
- Judgments 1907 (Barcode 1120072)
- Judgments 1908-1909 (Barcode 1120068)
- Judgments 1910-1911 (Barcode 1120071)
- Judgments 1911-1912 (Barcode 1120073)
- Judgments 1912-1913 (Barcode 1120069)
- Judgments 1912 (Barcode 1120070)
- Oversize Judgment - Plats 1877 (Barcode 1146214)
- Oversize Judgment - Plat 1880 (Barcode 1146215)
- Oversize Judgment - Plats 1886 (Barcode 1146216)
- Oversize Judgment - Blueprint 1894 (Barcode 1146217)
- Oversize Judgment - Plats 1895-1910 (Barcode 1146218)
- Oversize Judgment - Plat 1897-1901 (Barcode 1146232)
- Oversize Judgment - Plat 1897-1899 (Barcode 1146235)
- Oversize Judgment - Blueprints 1898 (Barcode 1146236)
- Oversize Judgment - Plats 1899 (Barcode 1146219)
- Oversize Judgment - Plats 1900 (Barcode 1146220)
- Oversize Judgment - Plat 1901 (Barcode 1146221)
- Oversize Judgment - Plats 1902 (Barcode 1146222)
- Oversize Judgment - Plat 1903 (Barcode 1146237)
- Oversize Judgment - Plats 1904 (Barcode 1146223)
- Oversize Judgment - Plat 1904 (Barcode 1146224)
- Oversize Judgment - Plat 1905 (Barcode 1146225)
- Oversize Judgment - Plat 1906 (Barcode 1146226)
- Oversize Judgment - Plat 1906 (Barcode 1146227)
- Oversize Judgment - Plats 1907 (Barcode 1146228)
- Oversize Judgment - Plats 1909 (Barcode 1146229)
- Oversize Judgment - Diagram 1910 (Barcode 1146230)
- Oversize Judgment - Plats 1911 (Barcode 1146231)